Jonathan Zacarias

Seattle, WA | c: 253-306-6055 | jonathanazacarias@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate, dependable, and disciplined individual with full stack software engineering experience, and operations management experience. Has a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, practical leadership experience, outstanding communication skills, and a lifelong learner and growth mindset.

Experience

Ally Waste

Jan 2019 - June 2023

District Manager and Tech Developer - Seattle, WA. June 2021 - June 2023

- Managed 15 west coast accounts, ~35 direct reports. Increased associate retention by 22% and reduced operational spending in the district by ~ 33%.
- App ideation and testing (user requirements analysis and user experience for "Ally" app), website building and SEO (www.allywaste.com), and Salesforce Admin - Increased client retention by 4% over 1 year.
- Took over 3 challenged accounts in other markets resulting in contract renewals for all. Equipment maintenance and repair resulting in \$21,000 cost saved over 1 year.

Technologies Intern - Phoenix, AZ

June 2021 - August 2021

- Identified useful data streams across company operations to then develop proprietary business tools for providing data driven insights to executive, sales, and operations teams.
- Worked with a third party developer to integrate data, developed knowledge, and techniques into proprietary company apps.

University of Redlands IT Services

Jan 2019 - June 2022

UoR IT and Online Services Developer - Redlands, CA

Aug 2021 - June 2022

 Collaborated with DevOps head to resolve bugs and develop "Redlands API" features. Studied code base/ architecture, performed test cases, and did code reviews to create maintainable code and meet coding standards. Built web forms for budget requests from university departments.

Jan 2019 - June 2021

- Planned and developed a new student portal with a focus on the student employment website, currently in use by the university for all student employees (Sharepoint, Knockout.js).
- Worked at the help desk with technical questions (networking issues, hardware repairs, software setup).

Readiness and Acceleration Innovation Network (RAIN)

Project Team Lead - Tacoma, WA

Summer 2017, 2018

 Organized and coded for RAIN's 2017 and 2018 International Genetically Engineered Machine (IGEM) competition teams resulting in a bronze medal for the team in both years.

Education and Training

University of Redlands - Redlands, CA

2018 - 2022

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science. Strong course load in mathematics. President of university programming club, member of Google DSC, participated in ICPC 2020 and 2021.

2024 Web Development Bootcamp

Summer 2024

Completed a course on current web development technologies and standards.

Skills

Programming Languages:

JavaScript (JSX, EJS, TS), Java, Python, HTML, CSS, C++

Development Tools/ Platforms:

VS, Git, Git Kraken, GitHub, Dev Ops, Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu, Arch), ProxMox, many more.

Frameworks/ Libraries:

React, React Router Dom, Express, Node, Passport, Axios, Flask, Pandas, many more.

Databases:

PostgreSQL, PGAdmin 4, MongoDB

Software Engineering/ Architecture:

REST/ RESTful APIs, GraphQL, wireframes, Agile model, code review, product engineering, system architecture, stakeholder collaboration, unit testing/ test cases.

Teamwork, leadership, and Interpersonal:

Communication, accountability, empowering/ encouraging others

Honors

Ally Waste Services September 2022 district manager of the month

2022 president's Achievement Award

First generation student "Juggler" award: (time manage many tasks and activities)

Other

Certifications:

2024 Web Development Bootcamp, W3Schools JavaScript, 2022 Salesforce Administrator, CompTIA Network+ in progress

Languages:

Spanish, learning ASL

Hobbies:

Grandmaster at Risk Global Domination, Vehicle mechanics/ flipping, Full stack projects.